https://us.looptackle.com/privacy-policy/

Last modified: 29/4/2019
LOOP Tackle Design AB (“LOOP Tackle Design”, “we”, “our” or “us”) care about your privacy. In this privacy policy, we inform you about how we process your personal data and what rights you have. Please read this privacy policy together with any other notice or privacy policy that we may provide to you on specific occasions when we collect or process personal data about you.
Table of Contents
Controller
If you must share your personal data with us
How we share your personal data
Transfer of personal data outside the EU/EEA
Your rights
Purpose and legal bases for the processing of your personal data
Children Under the Age of 13
Your California Privacy Rights [CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS ONLY]
Changes to this privacy policy
Controller
LOOP Tackle Design AB, corporate identity number 556225-0471 with postal address Box 6064, 192 06 Sollentuna, Sweden is the controller of your personal data.
If you wish to exercise your rights under this Policy or get in contact with us regarding our processing of your personal data, you can do this by contacting us by telephone 0854410190 or by e-mail info@looptackle.se.
If you must share your personal data with us
This policy applies to information we collect:
On our website located at looptackle.com (the “Website”).
When you contact us for information or for customer service purposes.
When you make a purchase.
When you create or maintain a customer account.
It does not apply to information collected by:
Any third party, including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website.
We need to process some of your personal data in order to be able to conclude and administrate your purchase, provide your customer account and to be able to comply with regulatory requirements. You must therefore provide these personal information to us.
If you do not provide such personal data, you will not be able to make purchases or create a customer account with us. What personal data you must provide can be found in the tables below where the legal basis is stated to be “performance of contract” or “legal obligation”.
If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our Website or provide information to us. By providing us information or accessing or using our Website, you agree to this privacy policy.
How we share your personal data
Your personal data is mainly only processed by LOOP Tackle Design. However, your personal data will be shared with third parties as set out below:
In order to have a functioning IT system and conduct our business efficiently we share your personal data with our IT-suppliers. Your personal data is only shared to the extent necessary for our suppliers to perform their obligations in the contract they have with us.
In order to administer your payment, we will share your personal data with the supplier providing the payment solution that we use. If you choose to pay via invoice, the payment service provider also may share your personal data with a credit agency to assess your financial situation.
In order for us to deliver your goods to you, and to handle any returns, we will share your personal data with the carrier that you choose in the check-out.
In order to handle customer service matters, we share your personal data with the company providing customer service on our behalf.
In order to give you and other potential customers customised marketing via digital channels, we will share your personal data with the relevant third party providing the digital channel.
We share your personal data with external partners that help us manage our marketing through the digital channels.
To comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.
To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of LOOP Tackle Design’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by LOOP Tackle Design is among the assets transferred.
To enforce or apply our terms of sale and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.
If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of LOOP Tackle Design, our customers, or others.
Transfer of personal data outside the EU/EEA
LOOP Tackle Design, our suppliers and partners will as a main principle only process your personal data within the EU/EES. In case personal data processes outside of the EU/EES there is either a decision from the commission ensuring that the third country in question has an adequate level of protection or appropriate safeguards in the form of standard contractual clauses, binding corporate rules or Privacy Shield, which ensures that your rights are protected. If you have any questions regarding how we share your personal data or if you want more information about the appropriate safeguards we have in place to protect your personal data, please feel free to contact us.
Your rights
Under data protection legislation, depending on the circumstances, you are entitled to a variety of rights when we process your personal data. We set these out below.
Right to withdraw consent and to object to processing
If we are relying on your consent to process your personal data you have a right to, wholly or partly, withdraw any given consent for the processing of your personal data. Your withdrawal will have effect from the time of your withdrawal.
You have a right to object to direct marketing and automated decision marking (including profiling), such as newsletters and customised marketing.
You have a right to object to our processing when the processing is based on a “balance of legitimate interests” legal basis (read more about what this means below and we set out in this privacy policy when we process your personal data on this basis). In some other cases, the right to object does not exist (e.g. since we must store your personal data). Please note that we are not obliged to uphold your objection, if we can show compelling legitimate reasons for the processing that outweigh your interests or if it is for the purpose of establishing, exercising, or defending legal claims.
Right to information and access
You have the right to obtain confirmation as to whether or not we are processing personal data about you and information about the personal data that we process, such as the purposes of the processing, categories and receipts of your personal data, and for how long we store your personal data. You can gain access to this information and obtain a copy of the personal data processed by us by contacting us as described in the beginning of this privacy policy.
Right to rectification
You have a right to correct or update any inaccurate personal data concerning you that we may be processing and to ask us to have incomplete personal data completed. We may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
Right to erasure (“the right to be forgotten”) and restriction of processing
Under certain circumstances, you have a right to request that we delete your personal data. This is the case for example where the personal data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed, or you withdraw your consent on which the processing is based and where there is no other legal ground for our continued processing for your personal data.
You also have a right to request that we restrict our processing of your personal data. That is the case for example when the accuracy of the personal data is contested by you, or the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to delete it and instead you request that we restrict our use of it.
Right to lodge a complaint to a supervisory authority
If you have any complaints regarding our processing of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority. You may do this in particular in the EU/EEA member state of your habitual residence, place of work or of an alleged infringement of the applicable data protection laws. In Sweden, the Swedish Data Protection Authority (www.datainspektionen.se) is the supervisory authority. You also have the right to seek a remedy from a national court.
Right to data portability
You have a right to ask us to transfer certain of your personal data we have about you to another company (data portability). We will provide your personal data in a structured commonly used, machine-readable format.
Purpose and legal bases for the processing of your personal data
Here you can read more about why we process your personal data, which categories of personal data we process and our legal basis for processing your personal data. You can also read for how long we process your personal data for each purpose.
You can also read about how we use cookies in our cookie policy which can be found here
You who contact us
Purpose: To communicate with you
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Communicate with you if you contact us via email, phone, our website or social media
Answer your questions
Name
Email address
Phone number
Information you leave to us
Balancing of interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest to be able to respond to your questions.
Retention time: We store your personal data for six months from the end of our communication.
You who made a purchase
Purpose: To administer your purchase
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Deliver your products
Carry out payment
Send order and delivery confirmation
Name
Contact details (postal address, email address and telephone number)
Order information (e.g. what product you have ordered)
Payment Information
Performance of contract
The processing is necessary in order for us to fulfill the contract regarding your purchase. If the data is not provided, you will not be able to make a purchase with us.
Retention time: The data is processed for twelve months after your products have been delivered.
In addition to the above, your personal data is also processed, for example social security number, by the payment service provider you choose use to carry out your payment. The payment service provider is a controller for the processing of your personal data and is responsible for informing you separately in this respect.
Purpose: To request reviews to you after completed purchase
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
To request product reviews and reviews about your shopping experience
Name
Email address
Balancing of interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest in contacting you with a request to review or rate the products you have purchased as well as your purchase experience.
Retention time: We will send product reviews to you three weeks after your purchase.
Purpose: To administer customer service matters
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Answer and administer your customer service matter by email, phone or social media
Name
Email address
Telephone number
The information you provide, such as order number.
Balancing of interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest in helping you with your matter.
Retention time: The data is processed for six months after completion of the matter.
Purpose: To comply with accounting act
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Comply with accounting act
Name
Postal address
Email address
Payment history and transactions
Legal obligation
The processing is necessary in order for us to comply with a legal obligation, i.e. accounting act.
Retention time: The data is processed for seven to eight years in accordance with applicable accounting act.
Purpose: Provide customised marketing in digital channels
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Provide customised marketing in digital channels, social media and third party web pages including sharing of data with those parties.
Email address
IP address
Cookies (purchase and browser history)
Balancing of interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest in providing customised marketing to you as a customer. Your data is processed for this purpose only if you have made a purchase and have not objected to marketing.
Retention time: The data is processed for twelve months after completion of purchase.
You who have created a customer account
Purpose: To provide you a customer account and give you a smoother customer experience
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
To create and manage your customer account.
To take security measures, e.g. ensure that only authorized logs in.
Communicate regarding your customer account.
Give you the benefits of having a customer account, this includes to provide you with the opportunity to for example use pre-filled information when you shop, to see previous purchases, to follow current purchases, to easily manage your newsletter subscription and to provide you with offers and other benefits.
Name
Email address
Password
Your interests
To give you the benefits of having a customer account the following is also processed:
The information which you have filled in during your latest purchase, this include that we store your name, email address and postal address
Order history
Performance of contract
The processing is necessary in order for us to create and administrate your customer account and give you the benefits which follows from a customer account e.g. give you a smoother purchase experience which follows from having a customer account.
Retention time: The personal data is stored for two years from the last time you were logged in. You can delete your customer account at any time, we will then immediately stop storing your personal information for this purpose.
Purpose: To improve our service
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Send requests to participate in surveys on the use of our service
Manage the responses you provide in the survey
Compile statistics of the results of our surveys
Examine how our service is used to take improvement measures
Name
Email address
Information you leave in the survey
Information regarding which offers you have used
Information on how the service is used
Balancing of interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest to be able to contact you with a request to review our service in order to improve it.
Examine how our service is used to take improvement measures
Information regarding which offers you have used
Information on how the service is used
Balancing of interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest to be able to improve our service.
Retention time: We will send inquiries to you as long as you have a customer account. However, we cease to store your personal data for this purpose if you object to receiving invitations for inquiries. We will only store the results of the surveys anonymously.
You who receive marketing from us
Purpose: To send marketing and provide you with benefits
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Send marketing and newsletters with offers and information
Send personalised and customised marketing so you get offers and information that we think you are interested in
Send information about your shopping cart if you have left our site without completing the purchase (including storing information about your shopping cart in order to be able to send you these reminders)
Name
Email address
Telephone number
For customised communication and reminder of your shopping cart, we also process:
Browsing history
Order history
Your interests
Balancing of interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest in sending relevant advertising to you as a customer. You are entitled to object to the marketing when the data is collected and in each mail.
Performance of contract
The processing is necessary in order for us to fulfil the contract regarding your customer account.
Consent
If you have chosen to subscribe to our newsletter on our website or given your consent via email, we will send the marketing based on your consent.
Retention time: The data is processed for one year from completed purchase based on the balance of interest, unless you have objected to receiving marketing from us. If the processing is based on performance of contract, we will send marketing to you as long as you have a customer account, unless you have objected to receiving marketing from us. If you have given your consent to receive marketing, we will send it to you until you unsubscribe to our newsletter or object to receiving marketing from us.
Purpose: Inviting you to events and competitions (marketing)
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Invite you to events and competitions
Administer your registration or participation in the competition
Name
Email address
Telephone number
Geographic location
Legitimate interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest in inviting you as a customer to events and competitions and administrate your registration or participation in the competition.
Performance of contract
The processing is necessary in order for us to fulfill the contract regarding your customer account. If the data is not provided, you will not be able to create a customer account with us.
Retention time: The data is processed for one year from completed purchase based on the balance of interest, unless you have objected to receiving marketing from us. If the processing is based on performance of contract, we will send marketing to you as long as you have a customer account, unless you have objected to receiving marketing from us.
You who have claims against us
Purpose: To handle the right of withdrawal, complaints or other claims
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Handle possible withdrawal of purchase
Handle possible complaints or other claims
Name
Contact information (postal address, email address and phone number)
Information from our communication with you regarding your claim (e.g. details about the current order)
Legal obligation and balancing of interests
The processing is necessary in order for us to act in accordance with consumer law and comply with a legal obligation. We also have a legitimate interest in being able to defend ourselves against a possible legal claim.
Retention time: The data is processed from the time you submit your claim and is processed as long as the process of the claim is in progress.
You who visit our website
Purpose: To improve our website
Processing performed:
Personal data we process:
Legal basis:
Examine and analyze how our website is used to make improvement measures
Gender
Age
Language
Country and city
Interests
Information from the unit you use to visit our website, namely IP-address, web browser, internet supplier, operating system, display resolution
Balancing of interest
The processing is justified by our legitimate interest to be able to develop and improve our website in order to give you and other users a better user experience.
Retention time: Personal data that we have collected in connection with an individual visit to our website is stored for seven months after you have completed the visit.
Balance of interests tests when processing data based on “legitimate interests”
As we state above, for some purposes, we process your personal data and rely on our legitimate interest as the legal basis for the processing. When assessing the balance of interests test, we have determined that our legitimate interest for the processing outweighs yours interests or rights which require the protection of your personal data. You are welcome to contact us if you want to read more about how we have undertaken this test.  Our contact details are as stated in the beginning of this privacy policy.
Children Under the Age of 13
Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any information to LOOP Tackle Design. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13.  If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information to us, including on our Website, make any purchases from LOOP Tackle Design, or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any other personal information.  If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us at info@looptackle.se.
Your California Privacy Rights [CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS ONLY]
California’s “Shine the Light” law (Civil Code Section § 1798.83) permits users of our Website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to info@looptackle.se  or write us at: Sjöängsvägen 15, 192 72 Sollentuna, Sweden.
Changes to this privacy policy
This privacy policy was last updated on the date at the top of this document and earlier versions can be obtained by contacting us. We may change this privacy policy from time to time and any changes will be posted on this page and, where substantive or material changes are made, we will notify you by email to the email address specified in your account.
Customer service
Shipping & Returns
Warranty & Repairs
Loop European Warranty
Loop North America & Worldwide Warranty
Sizing guide
Loop Aktiv
Log in
Privacy policy
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.Ok
